<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Considerations on the trade of Africa, humbly offer'd to the most honourable House of Lords, in behalf of the bill now before them</title>
            <author>D. T.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A95508</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T3</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R230028</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99899400</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99899400</idno>
            <idno type="VID">153361</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A95508)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 153361)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2360:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Considerations on the trade of Africa, humbly offer'd to the most honourable House of Lords, in behalf of the bill now before them</title>
                  <author>D. T.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>3, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1698]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Drop-head title.</note>
                  <note>Attributed by Wing to D.T.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing (CD-ROM edition).</note>
                  <note>With a docket title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Trade regulation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Trading companies --  Africa --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Commerce --  Africa --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:153361:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 52 -->
            <head>Conſiderations on the Trade of <hi>Africa,</hi> Humbly Offer'd to the Moſt Hon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ourable Houſe of <hi>LORDS,</hi> in behalf of the Bill now before them.</head>
            <p>THE Trade to <hi>Africa</hi> is allowed to be of Conſequence ſufficient to deſerve an Extraordinary Care. <note place="margin">The Trade of Conſequence.</note> The preſent Queſtion is not whether it ſhould be Preſerved or not. but how it may be moſt Advantageous to <hi>England,</hi> and the Colonies.</p>
            <p>To manage the Trade in a Company without a Stock ſeems both improper and impracticable, <note place="margin">Company Without a Stock impra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cticable.</note> on many Accounts; in particular, on Account of the Charge of Forts, Caſtles, and Treaties with the Petty Kings of the Country, which is very Chargeable, and alwayes requiring Secreſie and Expedition; and alſo to prevent the Deſigns of other <hi>Europeans,</hi> who have Forts and Caſtles on the ſame Coaſt: And if they could poſſeſs themſelves of our Forts and Caſtles, would ſoon become Maſters of the whole Trade, and exclude us.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And it is remarkable,</hi> 
               <note place="margin">All Nations ſupport Forts and Caſtles by a Joynt-Stock.</note> That where Forts and Caſtles are neceſſary for the Preſervation of the Trade, no Nation whatſoever have a Company without a Joynt-Stock.</p>
            <p>The Caſe of the <hi>Levant Company</hi> is otherwiſe: They need no Forts and Caſtles, being under Protection of a Government willing to Treat with, and able to Defend them.</p>
            <p>So that were it not for the Forts and Caſtles, which only an Incorporated Company, Trading upon a Joynt-Stock, can main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, Foreigners inſtead of leaving us any ſhare in that Trade, would ingroſs the whole. Nor is it to be ſuppoſed, that Private Perſons can, upon their Narrow and Uncertain Funds, contend againſt the Power and Craft of thoſe other <hi>European</hi> Nations who manage their Traffick thither by a Joynt-Stock, <hi>viz. French, Dutch, Danes, Hamburghers,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>But a Company, <note place="margin">A Company Regulated with a Joynt-Stock moſt beneficial.</note> with a Stock, to manage the Trade, allowing all Perſons the Freedom of Trade, on certain Limitations and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditions which may put them and the Company upon equal Charge in Trade, ſeems the moſt Reaſonable and Eaſie Way, both to Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote and Preſerve the Trade it ſelf in General, and the true Intereſt of the Colonies and Private Traders in Particular. For,</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:153361:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 53 -->
            <p n="1">1. By this Means the Forts and Caſtles, which defend the Trade, will more certainly be Maintained, for the Company will be bound to that, to ſecure their own Goods and Treaſure.</p>
            <p n="2">2. The Colonies will be certainly bettered by it; for the ſupply of Negroes will be more certain, and in greater Numbers: Nor can they be impoſed upon in Price, becauſe they, and all other Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, may fetch them, if they think fit.</p>
            <p n="3">3. If a Trade is carried on by a Company without a Stock, every Man is at Liberty whether he will Trade or no: And if the Publick Affairs ſhould make it very Hazardous or Unprofitable, they will decline Trade, and then the Forts and Caſtles muſt conſequently be loſt. For if few Ships ſhould be ſent thither, too little would be raiſed to uphold the Forts and Caſtles, which muſt alwayes be ſupplyed with Men, Proviſion, Stores and Ammunition from <hi>England:</hi> Whereas a Company, with a Stock, muſt Trade to imploy their Stock in War as well as Peace, and maintain the Forts and Caſtles for the Security of their Trade and Effects in the moſt dangerous Times, at the greateſt Expence, as the preſent <hi>African Company</hi> have done in the late War.</p>
            <p n="4">4. A Company with a Stock, with Liberty for others to Trade on Equal Charge, hath many Advantages to the Publick, by increa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing Trade, and by making room for Gentlemen, Widows, Orphans, or any Perſons out of Trade, to imploy their Moneys, and will give the Private Traders opportunity to improve their Stock and Induſtry, to the Advantage of themſelves in particular, and the Nation in ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral.</p>
            <p>Since then the preſent Bill gives Liberty to all His Majeſties Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects to Trade at a like Charge, <note place="margin">Preſent Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany may de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve the Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhment by this Bill pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed.</note> the Preſent Company ſeems to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve at leaſt this Method of Settlement in the Bill preſcribed, who have for Twenty Six Years paſt maintained the Trade, and preſerved the Forts and Caſtles at their own Charge, and have bought and built the Forts and Caſtles they now poſſeſs, have as a Company paid Eleven Thouſand Five Hundred Thirty Pound Eight Shillings Taxes during this War, have ſunk their Original Stock to maintain the ſaid Forts to ſupport the Trade, and have never divided above 3 <hi>per Cent. Communibus annis,</hi> and have during this War loſt above Two Hundred Thouſand Pounds <hi>Sterling</hi> in indeavouring to carry on this Trade, and notwithſtanding the ſcarcity of Money, and the ſaid great Loſſes, in the Year 1693 raiſed the further Sum of Seventy Two Thouſand Three Hundred and Forty Pounds for the preſerving the ſaid Forts, Caſtles, and Trade, whilſt ſome who oppoſe Settling the Trade have Enjoyed it without any Charge; And ſince the Peace have raiſed the further Sum of Fifty Seven Thouſand Ninety Six Pounds for the carrying on the ſaid Trade. By which 'tis hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly conceived they have given a very good Aſſurance, that under ſuch a Company the Trade can never be loſt, but the Forts and Caſtles will be ſupplied in the moſt dangerous Times.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:153361:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 53 -->
            <p>And yet by this Bill all Perſons may Trade, and their Factors and their Effects, be equally protected paying but an equal propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion for the ſupport of thoſe Forts and Protection of the Common Trade.</p>
            <p>The Company is by this Bill alſo oblig'd to give a true Account upon Oath of all Moneys Received and Paid on the Account of the ſaid Charge, <note place="margin">The Company to Account for what they Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive and Pay.</note> and to admit any Perſon on behalf of the Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate Traders to inſpect at all times the Accounts of their own Export, and of Moneys laid out for the Maintenance of the ſaid Forts and Caſtles.</p>
            <p>All which is humbly ſubmitted to the Conſideration of this Moſt Honourable Houſe.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:153361:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 54 -->
            <p>Conſiderations on the Trade of <hi>Africa,</hi> Humbly Offer'd to the Moſt Honourable Houſe of <hi>Lords,</hi> in behalf of the Bill now before them.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:153361:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 54 -->
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
